-=蓝光电影网=-
blu-raydisc.tv
下载更多蓝光高清电影-3D电影
请到-=蓝光电影网=-
- 这火没有烧到房子算是幸运的了 - 对啊
- It's lucky it didn't reach the house. - Yeah.
你知道么
You know,
等到六月份Milwaukee（密尔沃基）的工厂来了，工作岗位就多了
there's gonna be a lot more jobs at
that factory in Milwaukee come June.
- 我可以帮你走走关系 - 你不能留下我们，Henry
- I could put in a word. - You can't leave us, Henry.
她需要我们俩
She needs us both.
你能不能先不当妈妈的宝贝？
Can you stop being a momma's boy for one second?
我这不是伤害你的感情，可是，老天爷
I'm not trying to hurt you, but Jesus,
你也得自力更生一下吧
you got to live your own life sometime.
那女人完全可以照顾自己。。。oops
That woman can take care of her own goddamn...
矮油，晚上好
Oh, good evening.
从该隐和亚伯开始，兄弟之间就开始自相残杀
Brother has been killing brother since Cain and Abel,
然而这对我还是出乎意料
yet even I didn't see that coming.
我就跟躺在那儿的可怜的Henry一样被蒙骗
I was as blind-sided as poor old Henry down there.
而且显然有关部门也同样的天真
Apparently the authorities shared my naivet
换句话说，他们相信这个凶手的说辞：
In other words, they believed the young man's story
亨利跌倒了，他的头撞到了石头上
that Henry fell, hit his head on a stone,
死因是烟雾窒息
and died of smoke asphyxiation.
另一方面，如果有关部门不相信他
On the other hand, if they hadn't believed him,
Ed Gein就永远不会有机会招认那些
Ed Gein would never have had the opportunity to commit those
那些可以让他成名的凶残的罪行
heinous crimes for which he became most famous.
而我们，呵呵，也没法看到有关他的电影了不是么？
And we, of course, well... We wouldn't have our little movie, would we?
希区柯克噔噔噔
中字：三十    校对：小野
Sync, corrected by icephoenix
Here he comes!
这部电影一定会成为大事件
This thing's going to be gigantic.
我希望我能有百分之二十的镜头（应该不是这样翻译）
I wish I had 20% of the take.
今晚这无与伦比的反响让你吃惊么，希区柯克先生？
Does tonight's incredible reaction surprise you, Mr. Hitchcock?
不吃惊。当我还在筹划《西北偏北》的时候
No, when I was planning North by Northwest
我已经能听到观众的尖叫声和笑声了
I could already hear the screams and the laughter.
有什么问题么，美人？（美人摇头）真遗憾
Any questions, my dear? Pity.
希区柯克先生，你已经执导了46部电影
Mr. Hitchcock, you've directed 46 motion pictures.
你已经成为电影史上最著名的导演了
You're the most famous director in the history of the medium...
可是你已经60岁了
But you're sixty years old.
为什么不趁你现在的成功而退出呢？
Shouldn't you just quit while you're ahead?
穆罕默德的眼睛就是因为偷窥被人用箭矢挖了出来
Muhammad had the eyes of peeping Toms gouged out with arrows.
那一定非常疼
That must have been rather painful.
说起箭
Talking of arrows,
你看到纽约时报上A.H.Weiler写的短评么？
did you read that little snippet from A.H. Weiler's review in The New York Times?
他说他觉得影片的高潮”太过了“
He said he found the climax to be "overdrawn."
我倒是怀疑他这几年没有过高潮
Yes, well I doubt Mr. Weiler has had a climax in years.
“《西北偏北》让我们想起希区柯克早期的作品，
"North by Northwest reminds us of Mr. Hitchcock's
那些更加有创意的间谍惊悚片。”
earlier, more inventive spy thrillers."
这还有个（新悬念大师）的名单
And there is an accompanying list.
新生代悬念大师
The "New Masters of Suspense."
为什么明知原汁原味的还在他们还要找新人啊？
Why do they keep looking for new ones when they still have the original?
矮油，别多愁善感了，你也知道这玩意儿多容易激怒我
Oh, don't be maudlin, you know how much it aggravates me.
别读了
Just stop reading them.
你已经看这些文章一个星期了
You've been reading them for a week.
说实话亲爱的
Tell me, my dear,
你觉得我已经老了么？
do you think I'm too old?
没错，你是个活化石
Yes, you're a true relic.
而且还是一个肥胖的活化石
And lest we forget, a notably corpulent one.
你总是准确地知道人的痛处在哪儿，不是么？
You always know precisely where to plunge the dagger, don't you?
不就在一对肩胛骨之间么，这可是从你电影里学到的
Right between the shoulder blades. I learned it from your pictures.
那么我能问一下，你现在要去哪儿？
Where, may I ask, are you off to?
把你送到工作室后
I'm going to have brunch with Whit
我就去和Whit吃早午餐。难道你也想来？
after I drop you off at the studio. Would you care to join us?
我们刚刚才说过我太胖了
We've just established that I'm far too corpulent
不宜出现在大白天
to be seen in broad daylight.
矮油，当你发掘到新的项目你就会好起来的了
Oh, you'll feel better when you find a new project.
Peggy最近不是给你找了不少不错的书么？
Hasn't Peggy unearthed any decent books for you recently?
都是些书套包起来的安眠药
Yes, sleeping pills with dust jackets.
我怎么样？
So what do you think?
见得了人
Very presentable.
快点吧，你在摆臭脸了
Hurry up, dear, you're pruning.
（这一刻感觉《哈利波特》灵魂附体）
- 早上好！ - 希区柯克夫人
- Good Morning. - Ms. Hitchcock.
希区柯克先生
Mr. Hitchcock.
小狗们
Sirs.
希爱，你总会想到新的项目的。我敢打赌！
There's a project out there waiting for you, Hitch. I promise you.
- 但愿如此。谢谢亲爱的。 - 祝你有好的一天
- I hope so. Thank you, love. - Have a good day.
我如同走在水面上了现在。我需要新鲜的想法，新奇的想法！
I'm treading water, Peggy. I need something fresh, something different.
而不是找一帮昂贵的明星来做个花枕头
Without expensive stars to pretty it up.
福克斯已经是第三次邀请你参与《安妮日记》了
Fox is offering you The Diary of Anne Frank for the third time.
观众们难道会花一部电影的时间等着安妮
The audience would spend the entire picture waiting for Miss Frank
发现藏在阁楼的尸体么
to discover the corpse I'd hidden in the attic.
- 是吧，Nuncio？ - 对（意大利语）
- Wouldn't you agree, Nuncio? - Si.
MGM想让你考虑一下弗莱明的新书《皇家赌场》
MGM wants you for the Ian Fleming book, Casino Royale.
加里・格兰特加盟，是你的风格
Cary Grant. Definitely your style.
她不知道我才拍了部有他的电影么？叫《Xi Bei Pian Bei》
Doesn't she know I just made that movie? It's called North by Northwest.
而且所谓“风格”，亲爱的我告诉你，就是自我剽窃
"Style," my dear, is mere self-plagiarism.
对不起！
Oh, scusi!
漂亮、简洁、让人讨厌的小故事才是我们的目标
A nice, clean, nasty little piece of work. That's what I'm looking for.
我看看我能找到什么
I shall see what I can find.
- 你真是活该哈哈 - 对啊
- Serves you right. - Yeah.
你知道么，老希总是说你活在你的私人生活
You know, Hitch always says that your private life
总是比你演的剧情还要精彩的危险当中
is in danger of being more entertaining than any of your plots.
我很惊喜你让我陪了你整个下午
I'm surprised he let me have you for the whole afternoon.
而且你还那么漂亮
Especially looking so beautiful.
跟我说说，你最近在忙啥呢？
So tell me, what are you working on these days?
我么，嗯，
Me? Oh, oh...
我一直悉心打理我的花园
I'm satisfied working in my garden.
那可是一个幸运的花园
Oh! Well that's one lucky garden.
您的这些不断的阿谀奉承我真是消化不了了
All this relentless sycophancy is actually giving me indigestion.
我们开门见山吧？
What are you after?
我只是在想你能不能在这上面使用一下你的修建花园的手艺
I was hoping you may be able to apply your considerable pruning skills to this.
原来如此
Ah, all is finally revealed.
Whit，你还是很好猜的
Whit, you are a little predictable.
我最开心的事情就是跟你合作
The most fun I ever had was working with you.
有什么新的，亲爱的？
Anything come up, my dear? Anything at all?
没有合适的
Nothing suitable.
那是普通的水么？不然我就要给Alma打电话了
Is that water or do I need to call Alma?
爱咋咋地
Do whatever you want.
Anthony Boucher说Robert Bloch的《惊魂记》这本书
Anthony Boucher says that this book Psycho by Robert Bloch is
是“险象环生的娱乐”
"fiendishly entertaining."
听上去蛮恐怖的。城里每个人都不要这个故事。
It sounds ghastly. Everyone in town's already passed.
“每个人”都有谁？
And who is everyone, pray?
故事部门今早已经写完了一则新闻
The story department finished the coverage this morning.
这是关于Ed Gein这个来自Wisconsin的连环杀人凶手么？
This about Ed Gein, the mass murderer from Wisconsin?
没错
Oh, yeah.
“残忍的暴力、窥阴癖、异装癖和乱伦的视觉元素”
"Graphic elements of brutal violence, voyeurism, transvestitism and incest."
棒极了！和你的那些平庸的呆瓜完全不一样。
Very nice. Not your average run-of-the-mill nutcase, is he?
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
Peggy，这可是一个把自己老妈从坟里挖出来的男生
Peggy, this is the boy who dug up his own mother.
- 饿了么？ - 饿昏了
- Hungry? - Famished.
如果你一会儿感觉还行，只能吃半个葡萄柚
You can have half a grapefruit later if you're good.
听，希子
Listen, Hitch.
Whit昨天午餐的时候给我了一份他新书的校样
Whit gave me the galleys to his new book yesterday at lunch.
我已经想到一些改编它的好主意
I've already got some ideas about how we can adapt it.
最后会变得非常的高雅、老练以及充满悬念
It's elegant. It's sophisticated. It's full of intrigue.
你指的是那本书还是Whitfield Cook本人？
You mean the book or Mr. Whitfield Cook?
这肯定会一炮而红，小希！
This could be the one, Hitch.
我过会儿再读
I'll read it later.
那里面有卡路里你知道么？
There are calories in that, you know.
妈？
Ma?
妈...
Ma...
你不冷么？
Aren't you cold?
不要怕，妈妈
No need to be afraid, Ma.
我去
Oh, God!
你来读读这一小段
I just want you to read this little bit here.
它发生在一座汽车旅馆的浴室里
It takes place in the motel bathroom.
“Mary尖叫了起来，
"Mary started to scream,
“帘子被切割到底
"and then the curtains parted further
“一只手从中伸出，手里握着屠夫用的刀子
"and a hand appeared, holding a butcher's knife.
“正是这把刀，在这之后，
"It was the knife that, a moment later,
切断了尖叫声，还有她的头颅”
cut off her scream, and her head."
不错。Doris Day可以把它演成音乐剧
Charming. Doris Day should do it as a musical.
这根本就是小成本恐怖电影的俗烂桥段
That is nothing but low-budget horror movie claptrap.
但是如果交到某个非常擅长于制作惊悚片的人手里呢？
But what if someone really good made a horror picture?
想想这个惊吓值
Just think of the shock value.
在影片一半的时候杀掉女主角
Killing off your leading lady halfway through.
我说，你肯定感兴趣了，不是么亲爱的？
I mean, you are intrigued, are you not, my dear?
矮油，承认吧！
Come on, admit it.
承认吧！
Admit it.
恰恰相反，我倒是觉得是个巨大的错误
Actually, I think it's a huge mistake.
你完全不需要等到影片的一半。三十分钟后就杀了她
You shouldn't wait till halfway through. Kill her off after thirty minutes.
哈
Well!
Peggy，叫上你的下属们过来
Peggy, I want you to summon your minions.
- 下属？ - 现在！
- Minions? - Right away.
可以啊。下属有谁？
Certainly. And who might they be?
让他们将市面上所有的《惊魂记》买回来！
Get them started buying copies of Psycho.
- 你要多少本？ - 全部！每一本！全国范围内！
- How many do you need? - All of them. Every copy, nationwide.
搜刮所有的书店、图书馆，也就是所有地方。
Scour every bookshop, every library. And I mean everywhere.
《惊魂记》就是我下一部电影
Psycho is going to be my next movie,
我不想让任何人在看电影前就知道结局
and I don't want anyone to know the ending until they see it in the theater.
看
Look at that.
你确定要做这个？这一点也不是你的风格
Are you sure about this? This is so unlike you.
这才是重点，亲爱的
That is exactly the point, my dear.
敬爱的出版社的各位
Ladies and gentlemen of the press,
下午好
good afternoon.
我看得出来你们一直在阅读这篇关于Ed Gein的文章
I see you've all been devouring the article on Mr. Ed Gein.
关于一个暴力的男子
Violent chap,
以及这本书背后的我的真实的灵感
and the real-life inspiration behind Psycho.
我们所有人心底之龛都隐蔽这暴力
All of us harbor dark recesses of violence,
和恐惧。
and horror.
精彩吧？
Fascinating, isn't it?
当Wisconsin警察局突袭了Gein先生的农场后，
When the Wisconsin Police Department raided Mr. Gein's farm,
他们打开门。然后，哇！
they opened the door... And voila!
他们发现十个顶部被锯平的女性头颅
They discovered ten female heads with the tops sawn off.
请你传阅一下好么？
Pass these around, would you? And have a look.
这是人皮面具
Masks of human skin.
窗帘的拉绳上有一对嘴唇
A pair of lips on a drawstring for a window shade.
啊对了，还有一个装满鼻子的罐子
Oh, yes, and a jug containing human noses.
这真是是你下一部电影吗，希区柯克先生？
Is this really going to be your next picture, Mr. Hitchcock?
嗯是的夫人，那我的打算
Well, that is my intention, yes, madam.
我唯一的希望就是Ed Gein看起来更像William Holden而不是Elmer Fudd
My only wish is that Ed Gein looked a little more like William Holden instead of Elmer Fudd.
说起来，试试手指三明治。里面可是夹着真的手指。
By the way, try the finger sandwiches. They're real fingers.
我了个去
Bloody hell!
你别假装不对他没读你的剧本而生气了
Now don't pretend you're not upset he hasn't read it.
我没有生气。我是个大男孩了，可以接受这一切
I'm not. I'm a big boy, I can take it.
我很喜欢你的作品呢
Well, I loved it.
研究起来肯定非常有趣
It must be great fun to research.
你真的觉得他会读一下么？
Do you really think he will read it?
啊，说曹操曹操到
Ah, speak of the devil.
阿希啊，我跑遍全城想找一本《惊魂记》来看看
Hitch, I ran all over town trying to find a copy of Psycho
可是我连一本都找不到。
but I simply cannot find one.
- 我也想知道为什么会这样 - 好吧
- I wonder how that could have happened. - Yeah.
你为了我也得继续找下去
Don't stop looking on my behalf.
希区先生，你应该来一下
Hitch, you should come.
校车路过悬崖孩子们都比这个高兴
I've seen happier faces on a school bus going over a cliff.
但是他们没法不看，对吧？
But they can't stop looking, can they?
观众想被惊吓，Barney
Audiences want to be shocked, Barney.
他们想要新意
They want something different.
所以就是这了
And this is it.
每一次你想做些有新意的事情
Every time you want to do something different
像《申冤记》或者《迷魂记》，总有人会亏钱
like The Wrong Man or Vertigo, someone loses money.
所以我们就不能做有新意的事情了么
So we should stop trying to give them something new?
你还差派拉蒙最后一部电影
You owe Paramount one last picture, Hitch.
你就不能做一部像《西北偏北》这样的电影
Can't you do something like North by Northwest
而且是为我们做一部，而不是为米高梅
but for us this time instead of for MGM?
就做《惊魂记》
Psycho.
没有人比派拉蒙更尊重希区柯克这四个字
No one respects the name Hitchcock like Paramount.
你的意思是不接受么，Barney？
Are you telling me "no," Barney?
我觉得你没明白我的意思
I think you know me better than that, Hitch.
这算什么
What a putz.
你知道他的家族在创建这些电影宫殿之前是做什么的？
You know what his family did before they built those movie palaces?
开杂货店的
Ran a grocery store.
我父亲也曾经营杂货店
My father ran a grocery store.
对啊，这正是我想说的，他应该表现出更多的尊重
Exactly. That's what I'm saying. He should show some respect.
他们觉得我江郎才尽了，Lew
They think I've lost my touch, Lew.
我和电视界的交情在他们看来使我贬值了
My association with television has cheapened me.
你指的是我那次帮你找的机会
Are you referring to that deal I got you
Bristol-Meyers付你2万9千一集的薪酬，并且底片仍属于你自己
where Bristol-Meyers pays you 29 grand
an episode and you own the negative?
我倒觉得这才是贬值
That's my kind of cheap.
我总是反反复复追求同一个风格
They just want the same thing over and over and over.
他们已经将我放在一副棺材里而现在正想把棺材盖钉死
They've put me in a coffin and now they're nailing down the lid.
希区柯克，我作为你的经纪人，绝对不会让这件事发生的
Hitch, as your agent, I will never let that happen.
你估计需要多少钱
How much you think you can make this picture for?
多多少少八十万
$800,000, give or take.
你今天回家挺早的
You're home early.
噢，这其实挺好的
Oh, it's lovely actually.
你没给Whit的书一个机会让我还蛮失落的
You know, I'm disappointed you didn't give Whit's book a chance.
Whit怎么想？他失落么？
And what about Whit? Is he disappointed?
他不会，他知道你的作风
Oh, no. He knows you well enough.
哎呀你看看这件衣服。反正也该买件新的。
Look at that! Time for a new one anyway.
你应该多用用这池塘，亲爱的，特别是趁你腿脚还利索的时候
Well you'd better enjoy the pool, my dear, while you can.
《惊魂记》可能拍不下去了
We might not have it much longer.
为什么？
Why?
派拉蒙不愿意投资
Paramount refuses to finance the movie.
噢，小希，好遗憾啊
Oh, Hitch, I'm so sorry.
Lew还没能找到资金。或者说，没那么快能找到资金
Lew can't find the money. At least, not fast enough.
为什么不等一段时间呢？
Well why not wait?
不行
No.
可能要不得不要独立出片了，老女孩
Just going to have to go it alone, old girl.
自己投资
Finance it ourselves.
你是想卖掉整套房子呢，还是只卖这个池塘。
Are we going to have to sell the whole house or just the pool?
我只是想把这电影拍出来
I just want to do the film.
我只问一次这个问题
I will ask you this once and I'll never mention it again.
为什么现在一定要拍《惊魂记》？
Why this one, Hitch?
不仅仅是因为那么多人说“不同意”吧？
It's not just because so many people are saying "no," is it?
你还记得当年我们刚开始做电影时的快乐么
Do you remember the fun we had when we started out all those years ago?
当时我们一分钱没有，不是么？
We didn't have any money then, did we?
时间我们也没有多少。但是我们愿意冒险，你还记得吗？
We didn't have any time, either, but we took risks, do you remember?
我们做试验，我们创造出新的制作电影的方法
We experimented. We invented new ways of making pictures
因为我们必须得这样做
because we had to.
我只是想再找回那种自由感
I want to feel that kind of freedom again.
就像我们当年那样，你明白么？
Like we used to, you know?
我们打算做一个重建《惊魂记》提议
We are about to propose a restructured deal for Psycho.
说吧
I'm listening.
我们自己独立出资
We finance it independently.
阿希放弃他的导演费用。派拉蒙只负责发行，
Hitch waives his directorial fee. Paramount only distributes it,
40%的收益归派拉蒙所有（但愿没翻译错）
in exchange for 40% of the profits.
有意思。但是派拉蒙为什么发行？
Interesting. But what exactly is Paramount distributing?
这不还是那部怪胎穿着妈妈的裙子干谋杀的电影么？
Is this still a picture about a queer killing people in his mother's dress?
这部电影其实是代表了希区柯克的名声
What this picture is about is the reputation of Alfred Hitchcock.
- 没人不同意这一点 - Barney
- No one is arguing that. - Barney,
其实很简单
it's very simple.
这就是希区柯克下一部电影
This is Mr. Hitchcock's next film.
干不干这一票，你决定
Are you in or are you out?
好，派拉蒙同意
Fine. We'll take that deal.
只要你能筹到钱
If you can get the money.
我们已经有足够的钱了，Barney
We already have the money, Barney.
支票应该开给谁？
Who do I make it out to?
如果这部电影不卖座，Alma
If this picture fails, Alma,
我们会吃很长一段时间的丢人的闭门羹
we'll be in for a long, humiliating bout of crow-eating.
- 会很精彩的 - 你确定？
- It'll be splendid. - Are you sure?
电影？从来没这么觉得
Of the movie? Not at all.
但是希区柯克？毫无疑问的
But of you? Unquestionably.
咳
Ahem.
- 我是Joe Stefano，很高兴见到你 - 坐下吧
- Joe Stefano. Good to meet you. - Sit down.
抱歉我迟到了
I'm sorry I was late.
我被心理诊疗的时间延误了
My shrink session went overtime.
我每天都去他那儿，但还是不够
I see him every day and it's still not enough.
我以为只有导演助理才需要去看精神科医生
I thought it was only director's assistants who needed psychiatrists,
而不是编剧
not writers.
你会去看心理医生么，希区柯克先生？
Do you see a shrink, Mr. Hitchcock?
我必须承认，Stefano先生
I have to confess, Mr. Stefano,
幻想才是烦恼我大脑的东西
It boggles my brain just trying to imagine.
你和你的心理医生每天都说些什么内容？
What you and your shrink could possibly talk about every day?
老三样：性、强奸和我妈
The usual: Sex. Rage. My mother.
早上好，先生
Good morning, sir.
让我检查下你
Let me have a look at you.
比看牙医还糟糕的事情只有见审查员了
The only thing worse than a visit to the dentist is a visit to censor.
不管怎么样，你都要控制好情绪
Whatever you do, Hitch, don't lose your temper.
- 再见 - 祝你好运
- See you later. - Good luck.
（海斯）法典肯定不允许你的这部电影
The Code will absolutely not permit you
有一把刀插入女性的身体
to show a knife penetrating a woman's flesh.
我向你保证，Geoffrey
I assure you, Geoffrey,
我的杀人犯一直是品味和谨慎的典范
my murders are always models of taste and discretion.
电影会有不恰当的裸体暗示
Is there any improper suggestion of nudity in this
在这段浴室谋杀戏当中么？
murder scene in the shower?
女主角不会裸体，她会带着浴帽。。。
She won't be nude. She'll be wearing a shower cap.
我们也许允许一个从浴室窗户外面拍摄的
We might accept a shot from outside the bathroom window
Marion的过肩黑色轮廓的镜头，
of Marion in silhouette above the shoulders.
而且还要在窗户有雾气的情况下
Provided that the glass is frosted.
感激不尽
Thank you.
然后还有那场厕所的戏
And the scene with the toilet.
真的非常有必要拍摄厕所
It is completely necessary to show the toilet,
因为Marion Crane尝试在马桶冲掉所有的证据
because Marion Crane attempts to flush evidence down it.
而未被处理掉的证据在这之后会被女主人公的姐姐发现
Remnants of which are later discovered by her sister.
这些证据，你要明白，是她无故消失的线索
These remnants, you understand, are clues to her vanishing.
没有美国电影觉得有必要展示厕所
No American movie has ever found it necessary to show a toilet,
更别说冲厕所了
let alone to flush one.
我想应该在法国拍这电影
Perhaps we ought to shoot the film in France
用（洗生殖器和臀部用的）坐浴盆来替代马桶
and use a bidet instead.
希区柯克先生，如果本部门送你一个禁映
Mr. Hitchcock, if this office denies you a seal,
而且我们现在看起来也正往这个方向上走去
and we're certainly heading in that direction,
你的电影将不会有资格在这个国家任何一个电影院上映
your movie will not be released in a single theater in this country.
到那时你再开玩笑吧
Will you be making jokes then?
每个在好莱坞的人都恨我
Everyone in Hollywood resents me.
我为他们赚了成千上万的钱
I make them millions of dollars,
而且每年还要参加那些无聊的颁奖晚宴
and every year I sit at those dreadful award show dinners,
等着某个人来说一句“你真牛”
waiting for someone just to say, "You're good."
他们从拒绝我的那一瞬间中获取病态的快乐
They take sadistic pleasure in denying me that one little moment.
那一定很受伤
That must hurt.
伤得很深，Ed，非常深
Deeply, Ed. Deeply.
不好意思，医生。我只是不习惯这个
Sorry, doctor. I'm just not used to this...
过程
process.
就把我想象成你个朋友
Just think of me more like a friend.
这些冲动我到现在为止变得越来越多
It's just that more and more I've been having these...
impulses.
什么冲动？
What kind of impulses?
强烈的冲动
Strong ones.
这个
Here.
Lazar告诉我他非常想和你合作
The Lazar Office tell me he's crazy to work with you.
告诉他他不应该让他的客户在电视上过分曝光
Tell Swifty Lazar he should not have overexposed his client on television.
不像有一些事情我们可以提一下
Unlike some we could mention.
- Anthony Perkins - 噢。。
- Anthony Perkins. - Oh...
想想他能给角色Norman带去多少的二重性
Think of the duality he could bring to the role of Norman.
多少暴戾隐藏在这个小男孩的笑容里
The rage lurking beneath that little boy grin.
他的迷人气质让人从不察觉到他的秘密
The winsome charm he uses to keep from being found out.
为什么，Alma？你不会是在暗示Perkins先生是？
Why, Alma, you're not suggesting Mr. Perkins is...?
嗯~
Hm.
什么？
What?
我喜欢你的办公室
I like your office.
我已经数不过来看过多少次《火车怪客》了
I can't count how many times I've seen Strangers on a Train.
还有《夺魂索》
And Rope.
好吧。Norman Bates合理延伸了刚才你提到的那种电影当中两个主角
Well, Norman Bates is the logical extension of those two characters in that movie.
他很诱人、敏感、承受着
Appealing, sensitive, suffering the terrible burden
被迫假装不属于他的一个身份的折磨
of being forced to pretend to be something he is not.
我已经受不了这些制片公司硬塞给我的浪漫陈词滥调的角色
I'm sick of all this romantic crap the studios keep shoving me into.
但是我唯一担心的是
But my only worry is,
嗯，饰演Norman也许太相似于我的过去了
well, playing Norman might cut too close to home.
为什么？
How so?
在我年轻的时候，我非常黏我的母亲
When I was younger, I was incredibly close to my mother.
黏到我以至于非常希望父亲可以就此死掉
So close that I remember wishing my father would drop dead.
而我爸确实死了，在我五岁的时候
And then when I was five, he did just that.
死于心脏病
He keeled over from a heart attack.
我一直有罪恶感，希区柯克先生
You see I've been guilty my whole life, Mr. Hitchcock.
你知道么，我光是看着你做这些就能起水泡
You know, I'm getting blisters just watching you.
噢，别抱怨了
Oh, stop complaining.
新鲜空气和运动对你是有好处的
A bit of fresh air and exercise will do you good.
- 我去喝点东西 - 不，不行。你要去搞定那个篱笆
- I'm going to have a drink. - No you're not. You're going to finish that hedge.
你要修好所有的
You've got to go all the way around there, all the way around there, all the way around there.
- 这不可能，我没法做完 - 你可以
- It's impossible. I can't do that. - Yes you can.
你知道，我在想，如果我能让Grace Kelly饰演女主角
You know, I was thinking, if I could get Grace Kelly to play the girl,
他们就会让我拍凶杀戏
they'd let me get away with murder.
这不可能。她是公主，这就意味着你根本请不到她
Well you can't. She's a princess now, which makes her permanently unattainable.
这让我更想要她了
And all the more desirable.
Deborah Kerr怎么样？Lew提起过她
What about Deborah Kerr? Lew mentioned her.
不行，她太苏格兰化了
No, she's too Scottish.
诶，Janet怎么样？
What about Janet Leigh?
我知道她基本上算是一个乖乖女，但是她在《历劫佳人》里表现得太出色了
I know she's normally the "good girl," but she was awfully good in Touch of Evil.
你还记得在Wassermans的派对上你曾经“提到”过她的身材么？
You remember how you always used to remark on her figure at the Wassermans' parties?
对诶
Yeah.
- 晚上好 - 你好
- Good evening. - Hello.
- 很高兴见到你 - 你真迷人
- Lovely to see you. - Charmed.
- 你好 - 你好，Janet
- Hi. - Hello, Janet. How are you?
见到你太好了
Wonderful to see you.
- 亲爱的，你看起来太漂亮了 - 谢谢
- Well, my dear, you look very beautiful. - Thank you.
真的非常漂亮
Very beautiful.
当然了，Simpson女士之所以会喜欢Windsor公爵的真实原因在于
Of course the real secret of Mrs. Simpson's appeal to the Duke of Windsor
她可以将一支雪茄变得像一支雪茄
was that she could make a toothpick feel like a cigar.
噢。我一直非常投入准备扮演Marion
Oh, I've been so immersed in preparing to play Marion
我都快忘记怎么大笑了
I'd almost forgotten how to laugh.
- 是么？ - 是的
- Oh, really? - Yes.
现在，你必须尝尝这里的香蕉油酥糕饼
Now, now, you must try the banana shortcake.
噢，不了，我吃不动了。谢谢。我必须要照顾好我的身材。
Oh, no. Nothing for me, thank you. I'm watching my figure.
是的，不仅仅只有你需要照顾。我们不用了，谢谢。
Yes, you're not the only one. We're fine, thank you.
George，给她来一份香蕉油酥糕饼
George, bring her the banana shortcake.
呃等会儿，两份大的吧。谢谢
In fact, make that two large portions. Thank you.
告诉我亲爱的，你还为Marion Crane准备了什么？
Now tell me, my dear, how else have you prepared for the part of Marion Crane?
嗯，我写下了她的整个历程
Well, I've written an entire history for her,
这看起来确实有点傻，我知道，可还是很有用的
which seems a little silly, I know, but it really does help.
- 一点都不傻 - 真的？
- It doesn't sound silly at all. - No?
要不你告诉我们她其中一个深藏的秘密
Why don't you tell us one of her deepest secrets?
她活在一个双重世界里
Well, she leads a double life.
在Lowery办公室，她喷着Tweed香水
At the Lowery Office, she wears Tweed perfume.
但是当她和Sam在一起时
But when she's with Sam,
她想都不想就用起了她最贵的香水
she recklessly breaks out her most expensive bottle.
Lanvin的“我的罪恶”
"My Sin" by Lanvin.
- “我的罪恶”？- 对的
- "My Sin"? - Yes.
上帝啊
Good Lord!
我确实有一两个顾虑
I do have a concern or two.
我是一名女演员，这点没错，但是我首先还是一个妻子和母亲
I'm an actress, of course, but I'm first a wife and a mother.
我只是出于好奇而想了解一下
And I'm just curious to know...
你想怎么拍摄这场浴室戏？
How are you going to shoot this shower scene?
是的，你还有福尔摩斯
Yes, you and the Shurlock Office.
如果只是，要拍上半身全身，嗯，我还没那么爷们儿
It's only that, well, from here up, I'm not exactly boyish.
允许我让你放松一下，亲爱的
Allow me to set your mind at rest, my dear.
我将会拍摄好几个不同角度的短镜头
I will be shooting short bits of film from various angles.
最后剪辑在一起，蒙太奇会暗示出裸露的信息
Cut together, the montage will only suggest nudity.
还有暗示的暴力
Suggest violence.
不会真的裸露出来
Nothing will actually be shown.
不过当然了，如果能够有一场你的洗浴的戏
But of course, having you in the shower
会让这部分，嗯，更加挑逗
would make it all the more, well, titillating.
我先离开一下
Will you excuse me?
Alma，怎么在这里见到你了
Alma, dear, how lovely to see you.
噢，你好，Lillian
Oh, hello, Lillian.
你气色看起来不怎么样啊
You're looking a little pale.
这也不奇怪，因为你丈夫做的那么诡异的事情
No wonder with that thing your husband's working on now.
你肯定不同意的
You can't possibly approve.
干嘛要让他做这么没有品位的事情
Why are you letting him do something so tasteless?
亲爱的，你倒是干嘛那么气色差？这无非就是一部电影
Don't upset yourself, darling. It's only a bloody movie.
你居然让Vera Miles演姐姐
I can't believe you made Vera Miles play the sister.
反正她还在合同期内，总要用一下她不是么
Well, I've still got her under contract. May as well get something out of her.
她可是一个从来不领情的人，你难道不觉得么？
Rather a thankless role, don't you think?
是非常的不领情
For an utterly thankless girl.
太倒胃口了
Horrible.
那个老家伙真的对我不满呢
The old man really is unhappy with me, isn't he?
等下你先试试他给你挑的内衣
Wait till you see the undergarments he has picked out for you.
这样，好吧。我就告诉自己
Okay. Well, I am just going to have to keep telling myself,
这是给他拍的最后一部电影，之后我就自由了
one more picture and I'm free as a bird.
我做好了一份我们哪儿可以节省的清单？
So I've made a list of places where we can tighten our belts.
啊？
Huh?
我们都可以学习一下节俭的技巧，不是么阿弗？
We could all learn the art of self-restraint, couldn't we, Alfred?
一周只请一次园丁、周末不请司机
Gardeners once a week, weekend off for the driver...
这怎么行。我们还是找别的方面来节流吧
No, that's impossible. We'll have to find other places to cut.
没有其他方面了
There aren't any other places.
然后，还有从巴黎的Maxim's运来的货物我们也得放弃
And there's be no more shipments flown in from Maxim's of Paris.
我们付不起了
We can't afford it.
Chasen's的鹅肝我们也吃不起了
The foie gras at Chasen's is more than adequate.
但是那些鹅是从Barstow来的，又不是从Marseilles
But those geese are from Barstow, not from Marseilles.
我们都要为了实现长远的目标牺牲一下不是么阿弗？
Yes, well we all have to make our sacrifices for the greater good, don't we, Alfred?
我去拿下刀子
I'll go get the knives.
我错了么？
Am I making a terrible mistake?
要是这只是又一部《迷魂记》怎么办？
What if it's another Vertigo?
你先拍下第一个镜头，一切都会好起来的
Just get the first take under your belt. You'll be fine.
穿好衣服了么亲爱的？
Are you decent, my dear?
- 早上好 - 早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
我还行吧？
Am I all right?
- 完美极了 - 哇
- Perfect. - Wow.
- 早上好 - 早上好
- Morning. - Morning.
我还想再谢谢你能给我这个机会，希区柯克先生
I want to thank you once again for this opportunity, Mr. Hitchcock.
你可以叫我希胖，把“柯克”去掉
You may call me "Hitch." Hold the cock.
好了，看看你们俩，美国最受欢迎的邻家男孩女孩
Well look at you two. America's favorite boy and girl next door.
是啊，现在又要搬进一座新的“邻家”
Yes, and we're about to move to a whole new neighborhood.
- Janet、Tony早上好 - 早上好Vera
- Morning, Janet. Morning, Tony. - Morning, Vera.
- 谢谢你的衣服 - 你真的喜欢么？
- Thanks for the wardrobe, Hitch. - Do you approve?
你的品味最好了
You're the genius.
还有一件事就是，我的剧本最后十页怎么没了？
One thing, though. My script is missing its last ten pages.
等我的Alma把剧本修订完了，所有人呢的剧本才能补上最后十页
Everyone's script is missing ten pages until Alma finishes the revisions.
你们刚好赶上宣誓
You're just in time for the Oath.
- 什么？ - 宣誓
- The what? - The Oath.
- 早上好各位 - 早上好
- Good morning, everyone. - Good morning.
麻烦各位举起你们的右手
Would you all raise your right hands?
你也一样，Vera Miles
That includes you, Vera Miles.
- 我郑重地承诺 - 我郑重地承诺
- I do solemnly promise... - I do solemnly promise...
我不会把
- That I will not divulge... - That I will not divulge...
《惊魂记》的剧情和秘密泄露给
- The plot nor the many secrets of Psycho... - The plot nor the many secrets of Psycho...
朋友、亲人
- To friends, relatives... - To friends, relatives...
记者
- Trade reporters... - Trade reporters...
甚至透露给快退休的Dwight D. Eisenhower总统
Not even outgoing President Dwight D. Eisenhower.
非常感谢大家的配合
Thank you all very much.
这就是，Norman的私密小空间
Here we are, Norman's inner sanctum.
希胖
Now, Hitch.
能不能解释一下为什么我要看Marion脱衣服？
Explain to me why I'm watching Marion undress?
我觉得这应该算是冒犯我了
I feel like I should take offense at that.
也许是因为Norman曾经偷看过她老妈
Perhaps Norman secretly watched his mother
准备每夜的沐浴
preparing for her nightly bath.
嗯对，或许浴室门上也有一个小窗户
Yes, maybe there was a transom over the bathroom door?
没错，他可以站在一张椅子上就能偷窥到
Yeah, which he could access by climbing on a chair,
只要他不发出任何声响
so long as he was stealthy.
一个男生第一个见到的裸体女性往往就是通过偷窥母亲
A boy's first glimpse of a naked woman is usually his mother.
所以我还活在过去
So I'm reliving the past,
在Marion身上重复这种仪式
repeating a ritual with Marion?
别问我
Don't ask me.
我只是一个藏在角落的一台摄像机
I'm just a man hiding in the corner with my camera, watching.
摄像机才能告诉你和观众真正的真相
My camera will tell you the truth. The absolute truth.
希胖，我有个问题
Hitch, I have a question.
为什么这个洞在这一边要大些？
Why is the hole so much larger on this side?
是为了更好地偷窥你啊
All the better to see you with, my dear.
这样才能有更广的视角
At the greatest possible angle.
好了！
And cut!
非要我说，我倒是觉得演职员名单上可以改成
If you ask me, the credits should read
“编剧：Joseph Stefano、Alma Reville”
"Screenplay by Joseph Stefano and Alma Reville."
两个在意的人
The people who matter know.
我知道你慧眼独到。这真的能成么？
Alma, you always know the answer. Is this really going to work?
再说吧，明天见
See you tomorrow.
你好，路人甲
Hello, stranger.
- Whit！ - 最近怎么找不到你？
- Whit! - Where have you been hiding?
噢上帝
Oh, God...!
- 我刚刚修订完…… - 《惊魂记》我知道
- I've been finishing the revisions on... - Psycho.
- 你猜对了 - 阿希怎么样了？
- Mm-hmm. - And how is the old boy?
他正处于回归拍摄的狂野躁动当中
He is in a state of unbridled ecstasy now that he's back on the set.
你呢？你怎么样？
And you? How are you?
我最近还得赶的两千字的稿子给《读者文摘》
Well, two thousand words to do for Reader's Digest on
谁叫我跟一个爱凶杀的人结婚
what it's like to be married to a man obsessed by murder.
Alma，你应该休息一下了
Alma, you deserve a break.
让我们开车到Santa Barbara去
Let's drive up to Santa Barbara.
到El Encanto吃点我们最喜欢的Emilio炸的多汁牛排
We'll have Emilio fry up those juicy steaks that we love so much at El Encanto.
希区柯克先生，我们都准备好了
Mr. Hitchcock, we're ready for you on the set.
- 希区柯克先生 - 我一会儿就去
- Mr. Hitchcock. - I'll be there in a moment.
超市很多人么？
Long line at the supermarket?
不会啊，我以为会更晚到家呢
No. Actually, I'm home earlier than I expected.
- 想喝杯鸡尾酒么？ - 不，你也不许喝
- Would you like a cocktail? - No, and you shouldn't have one either.
- 那还没洗呢 - 我不在乎
- That hasn't been washed yet. - I don't care.
我和John Gavin一起拍了一整天了
Oh, I was filming all day today with John Gavin.
他可帅了
He's a good-looking chap.
但真的，plywood？的表现更抢眼
But really, plywood is more expressive.
我觉得他和Janet Leigh的情爱戏
I think his love scene with Janet Leigh
可能是全片最糟糕的一幕
may be most horrifying thing in the movie.
我想你的朋友Whitfield先生
Even your friend Mr. Whitfield Cook
演的还更好
would be better in the scene.
你完全可以亲自告诉他，他会非常开心的
Why don't you tell him yourself? I'm sure he'd be very flattered.
亲爱的，
You know, my dear,
可能我对你的好朋友太轻率了
maybe I was a bit too dismissive about your friend
我指的是他的那本书
Whitfield's book.
也不知道这周末能不能邀请他和Elizabeth来这儿玩
Perhaps he and Elizabeth could come over this weekend
然后照他们的意思让我好好看看那本书
and walk me through it, as they say.
Elizabeth是个好女人
Lovely woman, Elizabeth.
我想让你来一趟片场
I was hoping you could come to the set tomorrow.
好啊，我先看看明天有什么安排
Yes. Well, I'll see how my day shapes up.
好的
Yes.
你以为你可以逃掉。可是你逃不掉
You think you can get away with it, don't you? But you can't.
你以为它们不会出卖你，其实它们都会
You think they can't tell, but they can.
它们太明显了
They know.
你完全可以感受到那紧绕脖子的绳索
You can feel that noose tightening around that breakable little neck.
换句话说，你完全可以把钱悄悄还回去
I mean, you could return the money secretly,
但是那又有什么用？亡羊补牢了
but what would that prove? It's too late.
Marion Crane做事总是特别紧凑、体面
Marion Crane always so tight, so respectable,
拘谨、恰当、完美。高尚圣洁的Crane小姐。
so prim and so proper and perfect. Untouchable unsullied Miss Crane.
爸爸的乖女儿
Daddy's perfect little angel.
现在他们都知道了你那些隐藏已久的秘密
Now they all know those dirty little secrets you've been hiding so long.
和一个叫Samuel Loomis“哎呀妈真帅”的失败男人
Messy, sticky little lunchtime trysts
纠缠、粘黏的午间秘密约会
with that oh-so-handsome failure Mr. Samuel Loomis.
他们偷笑，他们会八卦，他们会窃窃私语
They'll smirk, they'll gossip, and they'll whisper.
甚至你那个古板严肃的瘦脸George Lowery小老板
Even your boss, straight-laced, hatchet-faced Mr. George Lowery,
为什么连他能嗅出你身上散发的刺鼻的性爱恶臭！？
why even he can smell the rancid, pungent scent of sex all over you.
好了，把那卷到时候洗出来
All right. Circle that and print it.
一次过就好了，而且争取所有的都顺利
Let's get this thing fixed once and for all.
我烦死了快
I'm sick and tired of it. Come on.
什么噪声？
Why's it making that noise?
- 什么时候修好？ - 五点吧
- When's it going to take to reset? - About five.
门开着
Come in.
喝点提神的吧
Thought you could use a little pick-me-up.
- 你人实在太好了，谢谢 - 不用
- Oh, you're so sweet. Thank you. - Not at all.
- 来，坐下 - 谢谢
- Here, have a seat. - Thanks.
你丈夫要是知道了刚才发生的事情应该会不乐意吧
I can't imagine your husband will be too pleased with what just happened.
嗯
Well, you know.
Tony和孩子们，有的时候他们说的话会让你大吃一惊
Tony and the kids, you'd be surprised what comes out of their mouths sometimes.
那倒是
That's true.
你也不太对他聊你自己的私人生活吧？
You haven't spoken to him much about your personal life, have you?
你是说希胖？是不会
Hitch? No, not really.
觉得你最好能够保持好这种距离
I'd keep it that way if I were you.
怎么说？
Why?
从他要求你应该有的发型那一刻开始
Well, it starts with him wanting to choose your hairstyle.
接下来就是帮你挑衣服
Then he wants to choose your clothes,
过滤朋友，最后甚至管到你应该生几个小孩儿
and your friends, and how many children you should have.
你知道《迷魂记》主角Jimmy Stewart有多惨么？
You know that poor, tortured soul Jimmy Stewart played in Vertigo?
他几乎成了第二个希胖
That's Hitch...
只不过换了个好看的皮囊
Only younger, slimmer and better-looking.
我不清楚
Oh, I don't know.
和奥逊威尔逊比起来，希胖算好的了
Compared to Orson Welles, he's a sweetheart.
看。他总是在监视着每个人
See? He's always watching.
- Jack，还需要多长时间才能准备好？ - 五分钟
- Jack, how long is this going to take? - Just need five minutes.
快点，时间不多了
Let's get a move on it. We haven't got all day.
这玩意儿怎么总是会烧坏？
Why does it keep burning out all the time?
- 快点弄好。有人接么？ - 还是占线
- Get it fixed. What's the hold-up? - It's still engaged.
希胖，我不看懂这第一场戏
Hitch, I'm stuck on Lila's first scene.
我不知道对抗Sam和侦探的时候应该用什么情感？
I don't know how strongly I should confront Sam and the detective...
亲爱的，就假装，假装懂么。不就是演戏么
Darling, just fake it. Fake it. You know how to do that. Act.
修订后的剧本呢？
Where are my revisions?
拜托，搬个灯架真的需要两个人么
Come on, does it really require two men to carry a light stand?
- 帮他们 - 就快好了希区柯克先生
- Help them. - I'll take care of it right away, Mr. Hitchcock.
自己掏钱的就是不一样
All the difference when the money's coming out of your own pocket, isn't it?
- 我们可以晚点吃午饭 - 好啊
- We'll have a late lunch. - Right.
- 我来订座，一点半 - 噢，Whit
- I'll make the reservation for 1:30. - Oh, Whit.
我要是没了你怎么办？
What would I do without you?
- 到时候再说，再见 - 再见
- Till then, bye-bye. - Bye.
Whit，你又忘了说什么了么？
Whit, what did you forget now?
Whit？
Whit?
是你么？
- 希区柯克先生，拜托了，希…… - 现在不行！
- Mr. Hitchcock, sir, please... - No, not now.
每个报社都在求工作照
Every press outlet is dying for photos.
哪怕是一张照片
If we could just get one photo, please!
滚出我的片场！不然我就叫保安了
Get off my set! I'll have security... Get off my set!
滚！谁帮我赶走这个男人，他是个害虫
Just go! Get rid of this man. He's a bloody pest.
让他滚，马上！
Get him off the set now!
- 你还好么？你看起来气色很差 - 我已经告诉你走开了
- Are you okay? You've gone very pale. - I tell you get away.
别像个跟屁虫一样，去给我弄杯酒
Stop following me around like a puppy dog and get me a drink.
- 现在连三点都还没到…… - 给我储藏柜的钥匙
- It's not even 3:00... - Now give me the key to the cabinets.
你好希胖，拍的怎么样了？
Hello, Hitch. How's the picture?
我听到一些有趣的消息
I'm hearing interesting things.
听到的东西总是难得的
It's a miracle anyone can hear anything
还是从Geoffrey Shurlock办公室噪声中听到的
above the noise coming from Geoffrey Shurlock's office.
你也知道，我不能光听啊
You know, I shouldn't be in a position of just hearing things, Hitch.
- 总该该给我看看一些片段吧 - 为什么？
- It's time you showed me some footage. - Why?
看看派拉蒙适不适合发行
To see if you're making a picture Paramount can actually release.
你应该知道，签约合同里写明了我有最终剪辑权
As you well know, my contract guarantees me final cut.
可合同里也写了
Your contract also says
派拉蒙有权不发行你任何
Paramount isn't required to distribute any film
给我们带来难堪的电影
that could cause us embarrassment.
反正我的电影不像你引以为豪的五部Martin&Lewis大电影
Unlike the last five Martin and Lewis films you're all so proud of.
我命令你给我片段
I demand to see some footage. Hitch!
我命令你给我看你的该死的片段！
You show me some damn footage now! Hitch!
不当保姆的感觉真好
You have no idea how wonderful it is not to have to look after someone.
哪怕只不当两个小时
I mean, even if it's just for two hours.
我们去哪儿啊，Whit？你还没告诉我呢
So where are we going, Whit? You haven't told me.
- 给你一个惊喜 - 噢我喜欢
- I have a little surprise. - Ooh!
- 你的司机呢？ - 我也想知道
- Where's your driver? - I've been asking myself the same thing.
我送你一程吧
Well, I can give you a ride if you'd like.
这车也太小了
Oh, my God. What a tiny car.
这是什么，我盯着看了好久
What are these things? I keep looking at them.
- 糖玉米。女孩儿们很喜欢 - 糖玉米啊
- Candy corn. The girls love them. - Candy corn?
我从Tony更衣室里偷偷顺出来的
I nicked them from Tony's dressing room.
真好吃
Oh. Very nice.
我以为你只吃Fauchon巧克力
I thought you only ate those Fauchon chocolates.
谁叫魔鬼把这东西摆在我面前
Needs must when the devil drives, my dear.
- 还好是我不是魔鬼（Drive的双关） - 谢天谢地
- Oh, luckily I'm driving. - Thank God for that.
他总是对他电影里的女主角有感觉
He's always had obsessions with his leading ladies.
唯独这次感觉像是特地针对我
Just that this time it feels like he's using them against me.
我觉得他就和其他伟大的艺术家一样
Well I suppose he's like any great artist.
没法生活在一起，不过尝试一下价值颇丰
Impossible to live with, but worth the effort.
你知道我们在一起之前，我可是他的老板呢？
Did you know before we got together, I was his boss?
他当上了导演助理才敢约我
He had to work his way up to assistant director before he dared ask me out.
- 真的假的？ - 真的
- Really? Huh! - Mm-hmm.
看到那座房子了么？
See that house over there?
- 看到了 - 你觉得怎么样？
- Yes. - What do you think of it?
- 位置不错啊 - 那是我的房子
- Lovely, isn't it. What a great position. - It's mine.
我才和Elizabeth聊过天，她从没提起过有过这房子
I just talked to Elizabeth. She didn't say anything about it.
她从来不知道这房子。没人知道
She doesn't know anything about it. Nobody does.
参观一下？
Want to see it?
- 谢谢，亲爱的 - 随时效劳
- Thank you, my dear. - Any time.
- 这个我能拿走么？ - 完全可以
- Can I keep these? - Absolutely.
- 再给你一颗吧？ - 不用了谢谢
- Would you like one? - No thank you.
- 那好吧，再次谢谢你 - 希胖？
- All right. Well, thank you. - Hitch?
怎么了？
What?
你和Vera之间发生了什么事？
What really did happen with you and Vera?
噢，Vera啊
Oh. Vera.
她本来要演《迷魂记》里的女主角
She was going to play the lead in Vertigo.
开拍两周前她告诉我她怀孕了
Two weeks before filming she told me was pregnant.
我本来可以把她捧红的
I was going to make her into a star.
但是她还是选择做家庭主妇
But she chose the life of a housewife instead.
我不明白女人为什么那么善变
Why do they do it, I wonder?
为什么她们总要背叛我
Why do they always betray me?
哇，很波西米亚风格嘛
Oh, very Bohemian.
租这套房子无非是图个清静
I just leased it for the off season.
一个没有妻子、孩子还有写作的地方
A place to get away from the wife, and kids, and writing.
Whit，我不希望你想歪了
Whit, I hope you don't have the wrong idea.
如果你想要认真帮我改编我的书
If you were serious about helping me adapt my book,
我真心觉得这个地方
I thought it might make the perfect...
再也合适不过了
hideaway.
乖大头乖
Relax! Naughty boys, calm down.
噢，我差点忘记告诉你
Oh, by the way, I forgot to tell you
我了你对那个故事的改编
I read your treatment of that story.
“去往什么的出租车”啊？
Taxi to... Where was it, dear?
- “去往Dubrovnik” - 对就是这个，Dubrovnik
- Dubrovnik. - That's it. Dubrovnik.
- 你想听听我的建议么？ - 当然了当然了
- Would you care to hear my opinion? - Well, yes, naturally.
那好
Right, then.
嗯，怎么说好呢，不过也没什么其他的表达方式了
Well, my dear, there's no other way of saying it, is there?
有种要死的感觉
It's a stillborn.
怎么说？
How so?
首先，剧情就有点混乱
First of all, the plot's a bit of a muddle, isn't it?
有些玩笑话也太像
Some of those jokes are awfully like the ones
我几百年前就已经在
we did so much better hundreds of years ago
《贵妇失踪记》里玩烂的了
in The Lady Vanishes.
而且你们的反派也太弱了。实话说，是弱爆了
Also your villain is rather weak. Well he's very weak, in fact.
但是我觉得最大的失败就在于
But I think the big failure
男女主人公之间的感情关系，你觉得呢？
is the relationship between the heroine and the hero, you see.
可能如果你没跟Whitfield Cook走那么近
Probably if you weren't so smitten with your friend Whitfield Cook,
也许你看的更清楚，不是么？
you'd be able to see that, wouldn't you?
当然了，我也知道
But then I suppose
女人们一但将心投入进去之后很难再让她们回头了不是么？
women never really care to face the truth when their hearts are involved, do they?
你哪知道什么男人和女人之间的事情
How would you know what really goes on between a man and a woman?
我的天啊，这也太脏了
My God, what a bloody mess.
- 别！ - 啊！
- No! - Ah!
强烈一点！强烈一点！
More! More!
- 不要！啊！ - 再凶狠点
- No! Oh! - Use some guts!
- 扎凶一点！ - 啊！
- Come on! No! - Oh!
- 愤怒点 - 啊啊
- More anger! - Oh! Oh!
别拍了
All right, cut! Cut! Cut!
我的妈呀
For God's sake!
谁能帮我找个靠谱点的凶手替身啊？
Will someone get me a proper stunt double?
把刀给我！情绪还不对！
Now give me the knife! Not yet!
给我无法控制的情绪！
Ungovernable rage!
这是杀人狂一般的暴力！
Homicidal violence!
好了。洗出来吧
Cut! Cut and print!
搞好了
We've got it.
Ed，这个时候别闹我
Oh, not now, Ed.
时候不对
It's really not the time.
你根本没法平息你的怒气
You just can't keep this stuff bottled up.
希胖，你还好么？
Oh, God! Hitch, Hitch, you all right?
- 你能听到我说话么？ - Alma……
- Can you hear me? - Alma...
如果让男主角和女主角在同一辆出租车里呢？
What if Bridget and Constantine get into the cab at the same time?
那如果他们俩刚刚好同时进出租呢？
Now what if they try and get in at exactly the same time?
- 嗯，什么是“刚刚好”？
- Yes. What do you mean, "exactly"?
我的意思是他们俩同时碰到车门
I mean they both reach for the cab door at exactly the same time.
- 他们瞬间触碰到对方 - 好
- They quickly touch. - Yes.
镜头先是给到他们俩的手，镜头升起，到它们的眼睛
We start on the hands, we pan up to the eyes, and...
非常棒
Oh, that feels better already.
- 你不接电话了么？ - 什么？
- Are you going to get that? - What?
听着，我已经告诉Peggy了
Listen, I've told Peggy
今天要给我拍好这个长镜头
you have to get this sequence shot today.
有什么问题？
What's the hold-up?
我们拍了十次，都太糟糕了
We tried it ten different ways and it looks terrible.
必须得用大角度摄影，这样才能显出惊讶
No, it has to be a high angle. You'll tip off the big surprise.
反正就是全程摄影
Just get the process shot.
如果他要挥手，那到底怎么拿稳摄像机啊？
How can he hold on to the camera frame if he's waving his arms?
你就把所以气体从楼梯最上面一层喷出来嘛
Why don't you just push all the gas from the top of the stairs?
不会有人因此受伤的
No one's going to get hurt.
这群笨蛋
What bloody idiots they are.
- 你这是干嘛？ - 不许再打电话了
- What are you doing? - No more phone calls.
- 可是 - 你不能再逼自己了
- Oh, but... - You're burning up.
你这是在浪费我们的资金
Burning off our money, that's what we're doing.
进度已经延迟两天了，而我还在这儿躺着
We're two days behind and I'm stuck in this bloody bed.
- 你以为你能去哪？ - 我必须去片场
- Where do you think you're going? - I've got to go to the set.
- 我们不能再延迟一天啊 - 你给我躺着，我去帮你处理
- We can't lose another day. - You stay in bed. I'll deal with it.
我才不想把你从你的绯闻男友那儿拽回来
I'd hate to take you away from your writing partner.
你好好给我躺着，艾弗
You stay under the blankets, Alfred.
- 希区柯克夫人你好 - 早上好
- Mrs. Hitchcock. - Good morning.
希胖大人呢
Where's Mr. Hitchcock?
不要因为我来了你们就不工作了
Don't stop work because of me.
我无非是管财务的
I'm only here as one of the two people paying your salaries.
- 拍到第几场了？ - 第173
- What's the scene number? - 173.
故事板在哪儿
Storyboards?
那好。Martin坐好在椅子上，让摄像机对着他
All right. Put Martin in the chair. Turn the camera around to face him.
我们来拍这后银幕下的摔倒
We'll shoot the fall against a rear screen.
那个镜头要用35毫米的（我感觉这里英字错了）
And, Jack, that len should be a 35mm.
你看，David，你也知道我们派拉蒙确实很喜欢Jerry Lewis的风格
Now, David, you know how Paramount loves Jerry Lewis,
可问题是这可是你已经驾轻就熟的题材，而且我是这样想的……
but this one is right up your alley, and I would consider...
Barney？
Barney?
Alma！
Alma!
你也认识David Kirkpatrick
You know David Kirkpatrick.
你好
- Hello. - Hello.
他正在帮Jerry Lewis做新电影
He's working on Jerry Lewis developing a new picture.
如果有用到他的地方他完全没问题
So he's free to help if you need.
没这个必要了
That won't be necessary.
- 但是你已经落后进度三天了 - 没错，不过我们可以补救回来
- But you're nearly three days behind. - Yes. Well, we can manage.
Alma，我们都知道这是一部什么电影
Alma, we both know what kind of film this is.
最适当的举措就是帮希胖完成它
The smart thing to do would be to help Hitch finish it.
谢谢你的关心，Barney
Thank you for your concern, Barney.
问题是这是希区柯克电影，导演只能是希区柯克
But on a Hitchcock picture, there is only one director.
都傻愣着干嘛呢
No need to gawp.
你忘记去检查一下厕所
You forgot to look in the bathroom.
一个像你这样的人，如果丢掉一条重要的线索……
A man like you missing a vital clue like that...
你想说什么？
What do you mean?
我妈说得好
My mother always said
“精益求精”
"If you want to do a job,
do it right."
来看一下地面
Check the floor.
仔细点看
Closer.
你还觉得他们俩只是“在一起写作”么
You still think they're just writing together?
你下一步应该怎么做？
What are you gonna do about it?
希区柯克夫人！
Oh, Mrs. Hitchcock.
我知道希胖最近身体抱恙，所以我给他准备了点东西
I know Hitch isn't feeling very well, so I got him a little something.
你人太好了，谢谢你
Oh, how kind. Thank you very much.
糖玉米
Candy corn.
他一直很照顾我
Well, he's always been very considerate of me.
其他导演一般都没这么贴心
I haven't always had that from my directors.
Janet，我想说
Janet, I'd just like to say that
以表现的非常敬业
you've been very professional.
效果也非常好
It hasn't gone unappreciated.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 见到你还是很高兴的 - 我也是
- Lovely seeing you. - You, too.
请问我能关小声点么？
May I turn it down?
你应该会很高兴我们片场的话事权已经捍卫下来了
Well you'll be pleased to know that order has been restored.
你总可以说句“谢谢”吧
And a "thank you" would be nice.
可我们还是落后了两天，超支了六万
We're still two days behind and $60,000 over budget.
那咱们就不开庆功宴了，这下就多了两千块
Yes, well I'll cancel the wrap party. That'll save us $2000 right there.
正好你也不用馋着要香槟和蛋糕了
And you won't be tempted by any champagne and cake.
你小心点，狗急了会跳墙的
Beware, all men are potential murderers.
而且还有正当理由
And for good reason.
够了！你到底在生气什么？
All right, what's this all about?
去海滩这件事你怎么解释？
Spending a lot of time at the beach?
没错，海滩上Whit租了座房子，我们俩一起写作
Yes. Yes, it's where Whit and I are writing. He's rented a place.
我想不会是个集中注意力写作的好地方吧
Hardly the ideal situation to avoid distractions.
实际上，这对两个人合作非常有帮助
Actually, it's very conducive to creative collaboration.
我已经告诉你了，修改它是浪费时间
I've already told you that treatment is a waste of time.
你对《惊魂记》不也是这么说的么？
Well, didn't they say the same thing about Psycho?
你和Whit在恋爱么？
Are you and Whit having an affair?
别想太多了
Oh, don't be absurd.
他在捣鼓些新的作品，他无非是想要点帮忙
He's working on something new. He just needs a little help, that's all.
那太巧了，我也在捣鼓新作品
Oh, what a coincidence. I'm working on something new
我也想要点帮忙
and I could use a little help, too!
你以为我之前在干嘛？
Well, what do you think I've been doing?
告诉我你为什么要和那个毫无才华的小屁孩
Why are you spending all the hours of day and night with that
花上一整天时间？
talentless mummy's boy?
因为那会让我比较开心
Because it's fun!
这部电影让我倍感压力
I am under extraordinary pressures on this picture,
至少你也应该全力支持我
and the least you could do is give me your full support.
“全力支持”？
Full support?
我们连房子都抵押了！
We've mortgaged our house.
让我提醒你一下
Might I remind you
我在这电影里参与了每一个部分
I have weighed in on every aspect of this film so far,
如同我在过去三十年你的每一部电影里的付出
as I have done on every film you've made in the last three decades.
首映完了之后，我给你你想要的想法
First time you show the film, it will be my notes that you want.
评论大好是我陪你庆祝
I celebrate with you when the reviews are good.
评论差了我为你哭泣
I cry for you when they are bad.
我主持你的派对，还要容忍你和你的那些女主角们的
I host your parties and I put up with those fantasy romances
奇妙关系
with your leading ladies.
然后还有当你到世界各地宣传你的电影
And when you're out promoting this film around the world,
我要么一直陪伴着你，或者在你身后
I will be there beside you, or rather, slightly behind you,
对媒体摆着笑容，哪怕我都快要流泪了
smiling endlessly for the press even though I'm ready to drop,
还要对那些当我不存在的人假装和善
and being gracious to people who look through me as if I were invisible
而且他们还把我推到一边，因为他们眼里只有
or elbow me aside because all they can see
伟大和荣耀的阿弗莱德・希区柯克
is the great and glorious genius Alfred Hitchcock!
然而现在，这几年我第一次斗胆
And now, for the first time in years,
去做些“希区柯克电影”以外的作品
I dare to work on something that isn't an Alfred Hitchcock production
却要遭到指控和非议？
and I'm met with accusation and criticisms?
我和Whit一起创作的作品让我愉快和有目标
The work I am doing with Whit gives me pleasure and purpose,
而且我不从你这索取任何东西
and it takes absolutely nothing away from you.
你给我记住了：我是你老婆，Alma Reville
Consider this a reminder: I am your wife, Alma Reville.
不是你合约下纠缠不清的妞
Not one of those contract blondes you badger
也不是受控你“特别”导演法的玩偶
and torment with your oh-so-specific directions.
嗯
Well...
我想也该说再见了
I guess this is goodbye.
你为什么不和我合作了
Why didn't you stay with me?
我可以把你捧得像Grace Kelly那样红的
I would have made you as big a star as Grace Kelly.
要是像她，我连自己去洗衣店都不行
Well, unlike Grace Kelly, I can pick my own dry cleaning.
我有一个家庭，希胖，一个家
I've got a family, Hitch. A home.
那个你一直想塑造的“金发女郎”形象
That blonde woman of mystery you're always after?
那只是一个梦
She's a fantasy.
是不存在的
She doesn't exist.
我曾经以为我已经理解你了
There was a time when I thought I understood you.
理解所有的女人了
Understood women.
Alma，我以为你下午会晚点来
Alma, I thought you were coming later this afternoon.
我以为你租这房子是为了写作
I thought you rented this place so we could write.
还是啊
I did.
- 你不会对谁说吧 - 不要怕，我不会告诉Elizabeth的
- You're not going to say anything, are you? - Don't worry. I won't tell Elizabeth.
我指的是对Hitch
I mean to Hitch.
Alma，我们不可能全是天才
Alma, we can't all be geniuses.
只有你的才华如此
You're incredibly talented.
不过到最后，我们还是希望他能够有一个更宽容地看这个剧本
But, after all, we want him to read the script with an open mind.
我们？
Don't we?
我不会再操心这件事了
I wouldn't worry about that, Whit.
警长大人，我担心的是
Sheriff, please, I'm worried.
Arbogast说他跟Bates夫人说了后会给我们打电话
Arbogast said he'd call as soon as he spoke with Mrs. Bates.
那已经是昨天晚上了
That was yesterday evening.
- Norman可没有结婚 - 他说那是他的母亲
- Norman isn't married. - He said it was his mother.
你雇的侦探说他在汽车旅店里看到Norman的母亲？
Your detective saw Norman's mother up at the motel?
而且她在二楼的窗户旁
In the upstairs window.
他从母亲那儿回来后就马上打电话给我了
He rang me right after she called out to him.
小姐，我想你的侦探是喝多了吧
Missy, I think your detective must be a few cups in.
Bates夫人十多年前就已经死于士的宁中毒了
Mrs. Bates died of strychnine poisoning more than ten years ago.
- 你说的是真的么？ - 夫人当时的尸体……
- Are you sure? - That body was...
这是我最喜欢的地方
This is my favorite place.
我只需要把门关上就可以让整个世界和我无关
I just shut the door and make the world go away.
在这儿你从来都不孤独的么？
Don't you ever get lonely out here?
我可以和我妈说话
I can always talk to my mother.
奇怪
That's strange.
我的天啊，我想我们发现了他藏身之处
Jesus Christ. I think we found his hiding place.
那是我妈的房间
That's my mother's room.
你们不能进去！
You can't go in there!
不许进！
Don't go in my mother's room!
希胖！
Hitch?
希胖
审核如何？
So what's the verdict?
他们只有一个字，这个字跟“好”没关系
Let's just say it was a four-letter review and it wasn't "good."
管他的
Screw him.
管他Balaban说什么，派拉蒙这个时候已经没退路了
It's too late for Paramount to back out, no matter what Balaban says.
还有一条路，就是重新剪成两集投放到电视
The other route is to re-cut it as a two-parter for the TV series.
顾及到预算还有希区柯克的金字招牌
Because of the budget and the Hitchcock name,
这是一个收回成本的好办法
we stand a good chance of breaking even.
我用《百战宝枪》让Jimmy Stewart成为百万富翁
Look, I made Jimmy Stewart a millionaire on Winchester 73,
而且那电影还不怎么地
and that was a dog.
这部电影我起码看完了
At least I could sit through your picture.
不过更重要的，还是要先听听Alma的意见
More importantly, what does Alma think?
我害怕你会责怪你自己
I was afraid you'd try to blame yourself.
我不是责怪
I'm not talking of blame.
Leigh，你怎么能在你还没想清楚时就做决定
Leigh, how can you make plans if you're still not sure?
Whit能为Colbert写戏应该很开心吧
Whit must've enjoyed writing for Colbert.
海滩那儿如何？
How was the beach?
冷得慎人
Cold and miserable.
就像咱老板的脸
Just like Barney Balaban's face.
可怜的Whit啊
Poor old Whit.
他不跟你合作，一分钱不值！
He isn't worth a damn when he's not working with you.
我也是一样
Neither am I.
我没法继续完成电影
I couldn't pull off the picture this time.
它就在那儿
It just sits there,
不愿意出来见人
refusing to come to life.
我想也没有别的词形容了
I guess there's no other way of saying it, is there?
跟Whit的剧本一样
It's stillborn.
我让你失望了，亲爱的
I let you down, my love.
你不该遭遇这些
You deserve better.
我该去喂喂大头们了
Better go feed Geoffrey and Stanley.
大头来吃东西咯！
Come on, boys.
我还是觉得就一个人哭哭啼啼的就好了
I don't think I can stand us both being maudlin.
那个模仿希区柯克风格的烂剧本我再也不帮忙了
That tiresome little Hitchcock imitation I've been helping Whit finish is done.
你知道现在只有一条路
You know there's only one solution to all this.
我们一起工作
That we get back to work together.
实话是，我还是想住在这间房子里
The fact is I rather like living in this house.
所以我建议，对你我都好，我们开始搞好《惊魂记》
So I suggest, for everyone's sake, we start whipping Psycho into shape.
你也许不是生活在一起最轻松的男人
You may not be the easiest man to live with,
但是你比任何人都知道如何剪辑一部好电影
but you know how to cut a picture better than anyone else.
除了你
Except for you.
第二个镜头手上的亮度要更好
The second take. The light is much better on the hands.
汽车发动了画面就停留在Janet上
Only cut back to Janet once the car's already moving.
节奏快点
Cut it tighter.
希胖你的坏蛋，你居然拍了裸体
Ooh, you imp, you got nudity in there!
她胸部太大了，镜头躲不开
Her breasts were rather large. It was a challenge not to show them.
你必须得剪掉这六七格
You'll have to cut those six or seven frames
她死了怎么可能还眨眼睛
where she blinks after she's supposed to be dead.
Alma，这部分我们看了好几遍
Alma, we've viewed the film a thousand times.
她没有眨眼睛
She does not blink.
- 里面进展怎么样？ - 特别顺利
- How's it going in there? - Swimmingly.
所有人都说这电影就像一只满是跳蚤的狗
Everyone's saying it's like a dog with fleas.
不行，绝对不行
No, absolutely not!
我不想让谋杀戏有背景音乐
I do not want music over the show murder scene.
但是Alma和我已经商量好了应该要放
But what Alma and I talked about is really going to play.
Bernie，这不是《迷魂记》，不是浪漫爱情电影
Bernie, this is not Vertigo. It's not a romantic movie.
画面要让画面自己说话
The images must work on their own.
没错，但是光靠“咚”一声是吓不了观众的
Yes, but you can't scare people just by going, "Boo!"
好啊，有种你放啊，你最懂了
All right, you do it then. You know best.
- 音乐必须参与叙事 - 你放啊，你放啊
- They have to anticipate it. - You always know best, just do it!
你必须退一步
Take a step back.
- 你怎么想？ - 我觉得我再也不敢洗澡了
- What do you think? - I think I'll never have a shower again.
- 希胖呢？ - 漂亮
- Hitch? - It's getting there.
我清楚地看到了刀扎和裸露的画面
I distinctly saw both the stabbing and the nudity.
你以为你看到了，事实上不过是画面的暗示
What you think you're seeing is purely informed by the power of suggestion.
我保证，当你看一遍最终版本
I assure you once you view the final version
配上Herrmann写的动听的旋律
with Mr. Herrmann's lovely, lyrical score...
动听的旋律是不会改变我的观点
A lyrical score is not going to change my opinion.
我们不会允许你上映
We're denying your seal.
Geoffrey，让我们俩单独聊聊
Geoffrey, would you mind if we had a word in private, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
你听好
Now look here.
我有一个最谨慎的建议
I have a modest proposal to make.
如果你同意保留洗澡的镜头
If you're willing to leave the shower sequence as it is,
我们会按照你的规格重新拍一遍开场的情爱戏
I will re-shoot the opening love scene to your exact specifications.
我甚至还欢迎你到现场亲自监督
In fact, I would welcome your personal supervision on the set.
按照我的规格？
To my specifications?
不过当然了，我亲爱的你
But of course, my dear fellow.
只要观众们可以完全理解
If only audiences could fully comprehend
你是多么努力地去帮我们娱乐他们
how tirelessly you work to help us entertain them
同时还要不让他们看到脏东西
while protecting them from filth and indecency.
从电影准备开始他就一直干扰你
He's been harassing you since you announced this project,
你都邀请他来片场了，他还不来
you invite him to the set, and he doesn't even show up?
你怎么跟他说的啊
What did you tell him?
我说我十分尊重他的工作
That I respected him deeply.
杀青了各位，非常感谢大家
Ladies and gentleman, that is a wrap. Thank you all very much.
- 我以为我们要重新拍这一幕 - 不过是一个伪装
- I thought we were re-shooting the scene. - The charade is over.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我也不是不能合作的嘛？
See, I wasn't that much of a monster to work with, was I?
完全不会
Not at all.
我希望我没给这添什么麻烦
I hope I was sufficiently loyal to the cause.
你绝对值得一枚紫心徽章
Worthy of a Purple Heart, my dear.
我希望你别介意
I hope you don't mind,
我说Bates夫人可以用一下你的更衣室
I told Mrs. Bates she could use your dressing room.
不会，这样非常好，非常好
No, that's splendid. Splendid.
没错，谢谢
Yes, thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们获得总局的允许了
We have the seal from the Shurlock Office.
现在，该把羊领到屠夫那儿了
So now, we lead the lambs to the slaughter.
派拉蒙说只允许两家剧院上映电影
Paramount confirmed they're only opening the movie in two theaters,
如同我们所预料的一般，而且没有首映礼
as we suspected. And no premiere.
没有口碑，没有前途
We don't get word of mouth, we're dead.
那我们还是赶快开始工作吧。Peggy，记下来
Then we'd better get started. Peggy, take a memo.
我们编一本手册来告诉大家如何推销《惊魂记》
We're going to write a manual on how to sell Psycho.
“给剧场经理的第一封信：
"My first instruction to Theater Owners:
请雇佣Pinkerton保安来保证我这个特别的入场规则”
Hire Pinkerton guards to strictly enforce our unique admission policies."
- 今晚可能有混乱 - “因为《惊魂记》的特别恐怖
- There may be riots here tonight. - "Because is Psycho is so terrifying and unique,
“保安可以帮助你搞定观众惊慌乱跑的情况
"the guards can help you deal with customers who run amok.
“在大厅摆上我们的倒计时
"Post our special lobby clocks
“提醒观众《惊魂记》什么时候开始
"to remind audiences of the starting times for Psycho.
本电影院经理让各位
The manager of this fine motion picture theater has been advised
在电影开演后保证不要让任何人进入放映厅
not to allow anyone to enter the theater once Psycho begins.
如此，如果有人还想从侧门、防火通道或是天窗
Now, should you be so foolish as to attempt to slip in by a side entrance,
偷偷溜进来
a fire escape or through a skylight,
他们会被暴力驱逐
you will be ejected by brute force.
语气有趣点好么
More playful, darling.
“为了更好地强化电影中的跌宕剧情、憾人的惊吓和悬疑
"To further emphasize the sheer, unrelenting shock and suspense of Psycho,
“在电影”完“之后，
"right after the closing title "The End,"
“我们强烈建议拉上银幕帘幕三十秒
"we strongly recommend that you close your house curtains over the screen for a full 30 seconds.
“这样做，《惊魂记》的恐怖
"By doing so, the horror of Psycho
“将永远烙印在观众的脑子里
"will be indelibly etched in the mind and heart of your audience.
你最真诚而坚决的，阿弗莱德・希区柯克”
Sincerely and emphatically, Alfred Hitchcock."
起码还有点人来看，希胖
Well at least there are some people here, Hitch.
我们为你们占了几个座
We've roped off some seats for you.
- 你先去 - 你确定？
- You go on ahead. - Are you sure?
我马上就上去。我去检查一下胶片。快去吧
Yes, I'll be with you in a moment. I'm just going to check the print. You go on.
那好，我们帮你占着座
All right, darling. We'll save you a seat, all right?
这边，希胖
This way, Mr. Hitchcock.
刚跟老板通了电话
Just got off the phone with Balaban.
他对你表示祝贺，正如大家所期望的，一次巨大的成功
He said congratulations. A well-deserved triumph, as we always knew.
“正如大家所期望”是么，哈哈
As we always knew, ha!
- 这是不是意味着我可以休息一个周末？ - 是的亲爱的。这段时间谢谢你
- Does this mean I can take the weekend off now? - Yes, dear. Thank you so much.
- Alma呢？ - 去吧去吧
- Where's Alma? - Go. Go on.
Alma，来
Alma, come here.
你知道，亲爱的，这或许是你事业中最大的成功
You know, darling, this could be the biggest success of your career.
是我们的事业
Our career.
Alma，我永远找不到像你一样美丽的“希区柯克式金发女郎”
Alma, I will never be able to find a Hitchcock blonde as beautiful as you.
我等你说这句话等了三十年
I've waited thirty years to hear you say that.
所以，他们才把我称为“悬疑大师”
And that, my dear, is why they call me the Master of Suspense.
就这样，亲爱的观众们
And so, gentle viewers,
《惊魂记》最后成为了我最重要的成就之一
Psycho turned out to be one of my greatest achievements,
我们俩的房子和游泳池最后也没卖掉
and Alma and I got to keep the house and the swimming pool.
不过你也知道Hollywood的规矩：
But you know what they say in Hollywood:
最后一部电影论成败
You're only as good as your last picture.
所以抱歉各位，我还是回去
So if you'll excuse me, I had better toddle away
开始展开下一个计划的奔波
to begin the exhaustive search for my next project.
不幸的是，我再一次没灵感了
Unfortunately, I find myself once again quite bereft of any inspiration.
然而，我还是希望有点小东西能快点出现
However, I do hope something comes along soon.
黑夜到了
Good evening.